Hello everyone, this video will introduce you to 3D clothing production, related tools for simulation control.
First, in the Connect tab, under the CloudTraining account, unlock the keyword simulation control.
First, double-click to download and open the frozen and back-up file.
In the 3D window, select the belt of this shirt skirt.
Right-click to select Frozen, and Ctrl-K.
The frozen version will appear light blue on the surface.
After opening the simulation, its position and shape will be completely fixed, and drag will not change or shift.
But it should be noted that there is still physical contact and collision between it and the normal soft clothing below.
Then we right-click on the plate again.
Unlock the belt.
Then right-click to switch to the back-up plate.
Right-click, Ctrl-J.
The back-up plate becomes translucent blue.
After opening the simulation, you can see that the back-up plate is not only fixed, but also no longer involved in any collision calculation.
The drag material will be directly worn through.
This also means that in the simulation, the back-up plate is a relatively frozen plate.
The calculation is smaller.
After stopping the simulation, return to the state of not wearing a mask.
On the plate, you will see the back-up plate again.
In addition, at the bottom of the back-up plate, there are options for the back-up plate and the sewing line.
If you choose the back-up plate and the sewing line, not only will the plate fail, but the sewing line relationship associated with it will also temporarily break.
And the sewing line will turn white.
Take this suit as an example.
On one side, the back-up plate.
On the other side, the back-up plate and the sewing line.
You will find that the back-up plate retains the sewing line relationship with the sleeve plate on one side.
On the other side, the back-up plate and the sewing line are reversed.
The back-up plate is equivalent to temporarily non-existence.
In addition, the sewing line relationship is also broken.
Stop the simulation.
Activate the sewing curve.
Simulate to stabilize.
In the actual application, when adjusting the clothing shape and simulating complex clothing,
you can use the freeze and counter-activation to fix the plate shape and reduce the calculation,
thereby increasing the simulation efficiency.
For example, now,
we need to move the belt from the left side of the shirt skirt to the right side.
If you directly turn on the simulation,
directly drag the belt plate,
you will find that the speed of adjusting the belt is slower,
because when the belt moves,
the whole clothes are involved in the simulation.
In order to speed up the simulation,
reduce the calculation,
we can freeze the plate that has direct contact with the belt.
Because the collision calculation of clothing and belt needs to be maintained,
that is, the collision,
the other plates that are not in contact with each other are all counter-activated.
Then turn on the simulation.
Adjust the belt position.
You will find that the simulation speed will be much faster.
After adjusting the belt position,
on the 3D window,
on the clothing,
any position double click,
select the whole clothing,
right-click to select activation.
Re-model,
the belt is naturally worn.
Here we see the reset arrangement together.
Open the reset arrangement file,
when the clothing appears,
how to fix it.
Take this clothing as an example,
you can see the bottom of the skirt,
the collar and sleeves have problems.
First see the bottom,
here the front and back pieces of the side,
are made in two different ways.
The front piece is added directly by the side tool.
For the wear problem in front of the eye,
we can directly on the side of the wear,
right-click to choose to arrange initialization,
you can quickly put the side
on the inside of the bottom of the front piece,
and then re-model it.
The back piece of the side,
is sewn on by the created side plate.
First, we can also use a similar tool,
put the side to the inside of the bottom of the back piece,
right-click on the side of the back piece,
choose to add to the inside,
you can add the side to the inside.
This is suitable for two plates,
used when there is a seam relationship.
If the outer layer of the fabric is twisted,
the impact is too big,
and the addition to the inside is not possible to solve,
you can select the side of the problem first,
right-click to set the anti-aggression plate and sewing line,
note that because it is necessary to completely eliminate the side of the side,
so it must be the option of the anti-aggression plate and sewing line.
Open the simulation,
so that the sound is natural and smooth,
then re-activate the side and add to the inside.
The problem of overlapping the wrong position of the top and the sleeve,
you can try to solve it by resetting the 3D arrangement position of the plate,
we only need to select two plates at the same time.
Right-click to reset the 3D arrangement position,
because these plates have previously used the arrangement point,
there is a memory in the arrangement file,
the plate can return to the 3D arrangement state,
re-modeling can be restored to normal.
If the button is stuck in,
right-click to reset the button.
The sleeve and the sleeve plate are also the same operation.
Select them together,
right-click to reset the 3D arrangement position.
You can see that the sleeve plate has been reset to the 3D position,
and the sleeve plate has no arrangement memory,
so it is flat.
In this case,
we can reopen the virtual model arrangement point,
select the plate,
re-select the arrangement point to be arranged,
or this side-mounted plate,
you can also directly right-click to add to the side,
to add the side of the sleeve that has a seam relationship.
After resetting the position,
open the simulation,
this dress is adjusted.
You can select the basic line of hidden clothing,
the internal line,
and the hidden sticky line.
Switch the clothing rendering type to the dense texture surface
to check and display the clothing.
Next, open the library,
continue to find the selection grid file and open it.
In order to make it easier to check,
you can choose to hide the internal line,
the hidden basic line,
and the sticky line.
The clothing rendering type can also be changed to the dense texture surface.
You can set it according to your needs.
When most of the fabric is in the model's body,
or when the hitter is in the opposite direction,
re-modeling may be very time-consuming.
At this time, we can use the selection grid tool.
For example,
see the sleeves of the back shirt are worn to the arm.
We will move the part of the plate blocked by the arm
to the correct side.
This can solve this problem.
Here, we first switch the tool to the selection grid tool.
In the 3D tool bar,
the third tool in the first row,
left-click and long-click.
Here, there are three modes of selection grid tool brush,
body, and lock.
We use the body as an example.
When using the selection grid tool,
the plate will automatically display the light green grid.
Adjust the 3D window angle
to the area facing the mask.
In the 3D window,
left-click the sleeve part of the frame selection and arm mask.
Try to select all the mask areas in the frame.
The selected grid will now become a high-gloss light.
Then see the 2D panel.
The corresponding grid will also display the light green,
indicating that it has been selected.
It can be found that
due to some panels being blocked by the arm,
it cannot be selected.
Therefore, on the 2D panel,
in the light green center,
there will naturally be a grid that has not been selected.
And these grids are also where we need to select,
and move to the outside of the arm.
Click on the blank area to cancel the selection.
According to the memory,
re-select the frame selection grid on the 2D panel.
If it is missing,
you can press Ctrl and Shift to select more.
If you have selected too many,
press Ctrl to cancel the selection.
After the selection is complete,
in the high-gloss light in the 3D window,
left-click to remove the positioning ball,
and turn to the side view.
Use the positioning ball to align the selected grid to the outside of the arm,
wrap it around the arm,
and then turn on the simulation.
The sleeve mask problem on this side is fixed.
The other side is also the same operation.
You can practice again.
The fold and cut of the front pants is the same.
You can use the same technique to undo the folding in this way.
This is the same process as before.
Let's first determine which part of the fabric should be on top.
Then use the selection grid tool to select this part of the grid.
Note here
that we need to move the original fold
out of the upper grid.
Combined with the green high-gloss area,
we can determine that it should be the inside of the red line.
The area on the left needs to be moved out.
and pull it out.
Note that you need to move the grid in the stop simulation state,
otherwise it will move with the surrounding grid.
If there is no adjustment,
you can select the grid you need again and move it out.
In addition, you can select the grid brush and brush tool,
but the way of selection is different.
The brush tool can be selected when selecting the irregular grid area,
and it is custom-made to create a selection area.
You can also press Ctrl and Shift to select more,
and press Ctrl to select less.
The brush can be applied directly on the grid,
and you can select the grid brush
that you want to select.
Right-click to divide the grid,
freeze, print, and so on.
Finally, you can see the setting layer.
Open this file.
Take this layer as an example.
Now there are two layers here.
The belt and elastic band of this layer.
We need to add another belt layer for this layer.
On the belt layer,
right-click and select the inner layer of the grid layer.
Because the new grid layer is only attached to the original layer,
it will exist with the elastic band of the original layer.
Direct simulation may not be stable.
Find the fourth tool in the second row of the 2D tool bar.
Set the layer.
First, click on the elastic band layer,
then click on the inner layer of the grid layer.
See the arrow point on the 2D layer.
Layer 1 is the starting point of the arrow.
The arrow points to layer 2,
and there is a plus sign on both lines.
This means that
we have set the outside of the front of the plate 1 on the plate 2.
Similarly, set the outside of the plate 2 on the plate 3.
That is, a layer of waist fabric on the plate 1,
a layer of elastic band on the plate 2,
a layer of inner waist fabric on the plate 3.
Such a structure.
After establishing the layer relationship,
the simulation will be very smooth.
Here is another detail.
We are on the left side.
Change the clothing rendering type to the physical surface
to distinguish the front and back of the fabric.
You can see that
the inner layer of the curtain is facing the outside.
In other words,
what we see is the opposite of the inner layer of the plate.
If we want the inner layer to be the front of the skin,
we need to turn the right arrow on the plate to the surface.
After turning,
the original layer logic changes.
Set the plus sign on the layer line.
It represents a plate on the outside of the front of another plate.
Now the inner layer is turned over.
The front and back are switched.
The elastic band is equivalent to the back of it now.
So we are going to change the plus sign of the connection to the minus sign.
On the plus sign,
the button can be switched to the minus sign.
That is, the plate 2 is on the front of the plate 3.
It is now on the side of the plate 3.
Finally,
about the more detailed explanation of the setting layer.
You can click the jump link at the bottom of the video.
Jump to know the skill video.
The above are a few tools to improve the simulation stability.
You can practice more.
If you want to learn more,
please subscribe to the channel.
Thank you for watching.
See you in the next video.